[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We'll now take a few minutes to instantiate this abstract algorithm we
سنأخذ بعض الدقائق في تمثيل هذه الخوارزمية المجردة
described and see what it looks like in the context of learning decision stumps.
التي وصفناها ونرى كيف تبدو في سياق تعلم فروع القرار.
There is other boosted decision stumps,
توجد فروع قرارات معززة أخرى،
it's a really nice simple default way of training on your data.
وهي طريقة افتراضية بسيطة وجيدة حقًا للتدرب على البيانات.
And so, it's one that we'll just go through a little further and
وهي الطريقة التي سنتعمق فيها بشكل أكبر
it'll help us ground some of the concepts that we looked at so far.
وستساعدنا على تأسيس بعض المفاهيم التي واجهتنا حتى الآن.
So here I've outlined the other boost algorithm that we discussed before in
لذا، قد قمت بتوضيح خوارزمية AdaBoost التي ناقشناها من قبل
the previous slides, but
في الشرائح السابقة، ولكن
just to be clear we're going to talk about linear decision stump for f of t, and
لأكون واضحًا، فسأتحدث حول فروع القرار الخطية لـ Ft
figuring out how to update it, figure out its coefficient, w hat t.
محاولين اكتشاف كيفية تحديثها، واكتشاف المعامل لديها، وهو W^t.
Our first step is figuring out how to learn the next decision stump,
خطوتنا الأولى هي اكتشاف كيفية تعلم فرع القرار التالي،
that's going to be f of t.
والذي سيكون Ft.
And this is just going to be like standard decision stump learning.
وهذا سيكون بمثابة التعلم القياسي لفرع القرار.
We're going to try splitting it on each feature, income, credit history,
وسنحاول تقسيمها وفقًا لكل سمة، من حيث الدخل والسجل الائتماني،
savings, market conditions.
والمدخرات وظروف السوق.
And figure out how well each of the resulting decisions stumps
واكتشاف مدى جودة كل من فروع القرارات الناتجة
are a way to data.
بالنسبة للبيانات المرجحة.
And notice that in our process we might split on income multiple times.
ولاحظ أنه في خلال العملية قد نقوم بتقسيم الدخل عدة مرات.
So in multiple considerations we might revisit the same feature.
لذا، فخلال عدة مراحل متكررة قد نعيد النظر في نفس السمة.
So we're going to try each of those features, and for
سنحاول تقسيم كل واحدة من تلك السمات،
each one of them, measure the weighted error on string data.
وسنقوم بقياس نسبة الخطأ المرجح بالنسبة لكل واحدة منهم على بيانات التدريب.
So for say splitting on income, the weight of the error might be 0.2.
لنفترض تقسيم الدخل، فقد تكون نسبة ترجيح الخطأ 0.2.
For splitting on credit, it might be 0.35.
وبالنسبة لتقسيم الائتمان، فقد تكون 0.35.
For splitting on savings, it might be 0.3.
ولتقسيم المدخرات، قد تكون 0.3.
And finally, if you split the market conditions,
وأخيرًا، مرحلة تقسيم ظروف السوق،
it might be the worst of these four decision stumps.
وقد تكون الأسوأ ضمن فروع القرارات الأربعة تلك.
On this weighted data, it might have a weighted error of 0.4.
فتبعًا لهذه البيانات المرجحة، فقد يكون خطأ مرجحًا بنسبة 0.4.
So, we're picking the best feature, the one that has lowest weighted error, and
وبالتالي، سننتقي أفضل سمة، وهي السمة التي لديها أقل نسبة خطأ مرجح،
so we're going to pick that first one split on.
لذا، سنقوم باختيار التقسيم الأول للسمة.
We're going to split on income, we'll get to the 100,000.
وسنقوم بتقسيم الدخل إلى أكبر من 100000.
And so f of t's, going to be that decision stamp,
لذا، فستمثل Ft فروع القرارات،
that says income's good to 100,000, if yes, safe, if not, is a risky loan.
والتي تقول إن الدخل الأكبر من 100000، إذا كان كذلك، فحينها يكون القرض آمنًا، وإذا لم يكن فحينها يكون القرض يشكل مخاطرة.
Now, the final question is,
والآن، فإن السؤال الأخير،
what coefficient we give to this particular classifier?
ما المعامل الذي سنعطيه لهذا المصنف المحدد؟
So all we have to is plug 0.2 into the formula, and if we plug it in and
كل ما علينا القيام به هو إدخال القيمة 0.2 إلى معادلة AdaBoost، وإذا قمنا بإدخالها
do the math, 0.69 is the result.
وقمنا ببعض الرياضيات، فستكون النتيجة 0.69.
So the coefficient of this first decision stem is just going to be 0.69.
لذا، فمعامل فرع القرار هذا سيكون 0.69.
Going back to the algorithm, we discussed how we are going to learn
وبالعودة إلى خوارزمية AdaBoost، فقد ناقشنا كيفية تعلم
this new stuff from data and how we figure out its coefficient.
هذه الأشياء الجديدة من البيانات، وكيفية اكتشاف المعامل.
Let's next talk about how to update the weight of i of each data point.
دعونا نتحدث عن كيفية تحديث ترجيح αi لكل نقطة بيانات.
So here's the intuitive process what happens.
وها هي العملية البديهية التي تحدث.
We have our data points and
لدينا نقاط البيانات
I'm highlighting them here depending on their income just like we did before.
وقد قمت بتحديدهم هنا وفقًا للدخل كما فعلنا من قبل.
But I'm going to make a prediction using this decision stamp.
ولكني سأجري عملية تنبؤ باستخدام فرع القرار هذا.
The question is how good is this decision stamp income greater than 100,000, and if
والسؤال هو، ما مدى جودة فرع القرار الذي لديه دخل أكبر من 100000،
you look at it, it makes mistakes in some of the data points and get others right.
وإذا قمت بالنظر إليه، فستجد أنه يحدث أخطاء في بعض نقاط البيانات ويأتي بالبعض الآخر بشكل صحيح.
So I marked the correct ones in bright green and mistakes in bright red.
لذا، فقد حددت النقاط الصحيحة باللون الأخضر والأخطاء باللون الأحمر.
And if we take the previous weights, alpha for each one of these data points,
وإذا أخذنا الترجيحات السابقة التي يرمز لها بالرمز α ،لكل واحدة من نقاط البيانات تلك،
I'm going to highlight where those weights were right there.
كما أنا موضح تلك الترجيحات الموجودة هنا.
We need to compute the new weight based on the formula above,
فنحن نحتاج إلى حساب الترجيح الجديد وفقًا لصيغة المعادلة بالأعلى،
which is standard formula.
والتي عبارة عن صيغة قياسية لمعادلة AdaBoost .
So, we're going to plug in the w hat that we computed, 0.69,
سنقوم بإدخال قيمة W^ التي قمنا بحسابها 0.69،
into the formula to figure out what to multiply each one of those weights by.
إلى معادلة AdaBoost لاكتشاف ما هو حاصل ضرب كل واحدة من هذه الترجيحات.
So, plug it in.
إذا قمنا بإدخالها،
You'll see that each of the -0.69 is a half, so
فسترى أن كل قيمة -0.69 هي نصف،
for every correct data point one is half its weight, and each of the 0.69 is two.
فسنقوم بالحصول على نصف الترجيح لكل نقطة بيانات صحيح، وأن كل قيمة 0.69 هي 2.
So for every incorrect data point, we're going to double its weight.
لذا، فسنقوم بمضاعفة الترجيح لكل نقطة بيانات غير صحيحة.
So I'm going to go row by row, for
لذا، سأنتقل من صف إلى آخر،
the ones in green I got correct, I'm going to half the weights.
وبالنسبة للنقاط الخضراء الصحيحة، فسأقوم بتقسيم الترجيح إلى النصف.
So for the first row there the weight before was 0.5 and now becomes 0.25.
وبالتالي، بالنسبة للصف الأول هناك فكان الترجيح من قبل 0.5، وقد أصبح الآن 0.25.
The next one was 1.5 becomes 0.75 because of their correct.
والنقطة التالي كانت 1.5 وقد أصبحت 0.75 لأنها نقطة صحيحة.
For third row I made a mistake, its weight before was 1.5.
بالنسبة للصف الثالث، فقد ارتكبت خطأ حيث كان يساوي 1.5 من قبل
Now I'm going to double it, I'm going to make it 3.
والآن، سأقوم بمضاعفة تلك القيمة، سأجعلها 3.
So it can go datapoint by datapoint and then multiplied by two, or divided by two,
لذا، يمكننا التعامل مع كل نقطة بيانات تلو الأخرى ثم نضربها في 2 أو نقسمها على 2،
the weight, depending on whether we got that data point right or not.
وهو الترجيح، الذي وفقًا له نكون حصلنا على نقطة البيانات بشكل صحيح أو لا.
Extremely simple to be able to boost the decision stump classifier, and
وإن الأمر في غاية البساطة لإنشاء مصنف لفروع القرارات في AdaBoost،
these tend do extremely well on a wide range of data sets.
فذلك يميل للعمل بشكل جيد للغاية على نطاق واسع من مجموعات البيانات.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]